A Guide to the Papers of Breece D'J Pancake, 1961 (1978-1979) 1979
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Breece D'J Pancake, 1961 (1978-1979) 1979
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10975-a
This collection consists of 63 items (1 Hollinger box, ca. .5 linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the University of Virginia Library on February 16, 1994, by John Casey, Charlottesville, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
The papers chiefly contain correspondence about Pancake's search for employment or other opportunities, including several copies of his curriculum vitae, two religious books and a Bible owned by him, and several of his short stories and English class papers. There are also two letters from Helen Pancake to John Casey which discuss the appearance of an article about Breece Pancake in American Short Story Writers Since World War II and a biography about Pancake by Tom Douglass.
Contents List
- Correspondence re Employment & Opportunities 1978-1979
- Curriculum Vitae ca. 1979
- Letters from Helen Pancake to John Casey 1993 Mar 24 & Apr 7
- Miscellaneous Papers 1979, n.d.
- Newsclippings re Breece D'J Pancake 1983, 1993, n.d.
- Short Stories & Related Material
  - "From Eros to Agape: Yorick's Journey" by Breece Pancake, with autograph corrections by the author 1978 Fall, TMs, 8 pages
  - "In the Dry" by Breece Pancake, with autograph corrections by the author ca. 1978, TMs, 19 pages
  - "In the Dry" by Breece Pancake in The Atlantic Monthly1978 Aug, printed, pages 52-58
  - "The Mark" by Breece Pancake n.d., TMs (EC), 15 pages
  - "Oral Narrative of Cabell County, West Virginia, as Culture Control" by Breece Pancake n.d., TMs, 21 pages
  - "Rat Boy" by Breece Pancake n.d., TMs (EC), 10 pages
  - "Rat Boy" by Breece Pancake n.d., near print, 10 pages, mimeograph copy
  - The Stories of Breece D'J Pancake"Afterword" (only) by John Casey, with author's corrections ca. 1983, TMs (EC)
  - "Time and Again" by Breece Pancake, in Nightwork, 5 pages, first issue consisting of 150 copies, with a letter from Jim Wilcox, November 9, 1978, of Doubleday 1978 Sep, printed
  - "Trilobites" by Breece Pancake in The Atlantic Monthly1977 Dec, printed
  - "Trilobites" A Screenplay by Mark Rance and David Selby based on Breece Pancake's short stories, with two letters to John Casey about the screenplay 1993 Mar 26, TMs
  - "Two Original Stories" by Breece D'J Pancake, A Thesis Presented to the Graduate Faculty of the University of Virginia for the Master of Arts ca. 1978, 2 TMs (EC)
  - A Bible presented to Breece Pancake by the Milton Methodist Church (1961), and two books by Henri J.M. Nouwen, Reaching Out and The Wounded Healer, presumably belonging to Breece Pancake 1961, 1972-75, printed